<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Medhat Omr Blog</title>
  <subtitle>I build Software</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/medhatomr/"/>
  <updated>2018-02-17T03:16:48.941Z</updated>
  <id>https://www.linkedin.com/in/medhatomr/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Medhat Omr</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Programming Land VISA Application</title>
    <link href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/medhatomr/2017/06/04/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://www.linkedin.com/in/medhatomr/2017/06/04/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2017-06-04T16:11:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-17T03:16:48.941Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, I’m Medhat Omr, a citizen of Programming Land. In Programming Land, we don’t have Europe, Asia, or Africa. Instead, we have Google, Github, and Stackoverflow. If you want to visit Programming Land, you need to have a Programming Land VISA, which I will talk about how to obtain one in the following steps.</p>
<h2 id="Step-1-Picking-a-language"><a href="#Step-1-Picking-a-language" class="headerlink" title="Step #1: Picking a language"></a>Step #1: Picking a language</h2><blockquote>
<p>I speak Spanish to God, Italian to Women, French to Men, and German to my Horse. - Charles V, Holy Roman Emperor</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In Programming Land, we speak different languages to different programmers too. For e.g.:</p>
<ul>
<li>Programmers chasing performance usually speak C/C++</li>
<li>Programmers in the Web Union speak HTML, CSS, and JS and/or one of the following list: PHP, Ruby, Java, C#, or Python</li>
<li>Programmers in Data Science and neighbors speak MATLAB, R, and Python</li>
<li>Enterprise Apps, most probably C#, C++, or Java</li>
<li>etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>Therefore, step number one is depending on who you want to speak/write to, pick the preferred language for them. In other words, based on your project type, choose the most suitable language for it even if it is new to you. It worth learning it.</p>
<h2 id="Step-2-Learn-the-language-you-picked-in-the-previous-step-and-master-it"><a href="#Step-2-Learn-the-language-you-picked-in-the-previous-step-and-master-it" class="headerlink" title="Step #2: Learn the language you picked in the previous step and master it"></a>Step #2: Learn the language you picked in the previous step and master it</h2><p>Learning the syntax and features of a programming language is like learning the alphabet in English or French. All the subsequent steps depend on it, like everything in any writing language depends on knowing the alphabet of that language. So, invest time in knowing your language. It will give you great returns in the next steps.</p>
<h2 id="Step-3-Learn-Object-Oriented-Programming-OOP"><a href="#Step-3-Learn-Object-Oriented-Programming-OOP" class="headerlink" title="Step #3: Learn Object Oriented Programming (OOP)"></a>Step #3: Learn Object Oriented Programming (OOP)</h2><p>OOP is like grammar in any writing language for me, not syntax; I didn’t map language keywords to the alphabet of a language to map syntax to grammar. Lots of programmers once learn the syntax of a programming language they stop learning about programming and start to program right away. Keep in mind, all time you spend in learning about programming will save you multiple magnitudes of time in debugging and/or maintaining your code afterwards.</p>
<h2 id="Step-4-Data-structures-DS-and-algorithms"><a href="#Step-4-Data-structures-DS-and-algorithms" class="headerlink" title="Step #4: Data structures (DS) and algorithms"></a>Step #4: Data structures (DS) and algorithms</h2><p>In this step is where you start building up your vocabulary. The more DS and algorithms you know, the more fluent you will be in your programming language. So I will let you imagine how is life without vocabulary, and you will know how I feel when I see code which has nothing but arrays and for loops.</p>
<h2 id="Step-5-Design-Patterns"><a href="#Step-5-Design-Patterns" class="headerlink" title="Step #5: Design Patterns"></a>Step #5: Design Patterns</h2><p>Congratulations, now you can write a whole project by yourself, but what about an organization? How will you structure your code? The answer is design patterns. Like we have listing &amp; classification, chronological &amp; Compare contrast, process, cause &amp; effect … etc. We have, the Multi-Tier architecture, the Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture or pattern, the Singleton Pattern, the Factory Pattern, the Observer Patter … etc. In future posts, I will write more about each step in details. However, in the next post, I like to write first about what tools do we use in programming land. Stay tuned and happy programming.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Hello, I’m Medhat Omr, a citizen of Programming Land. In Programming Land, we don’t have Europe, Asia, or Africa. Instead, we have Google
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
